ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
磁芯章鱼X
翻译
showeryhe
煮粥达人  累
翻译
电脑团  冬麟
静妹粒
翻译
大了个鹅
ET外星人
时间轴
孙了个大圣  chance-coco
电脑狂人
第三季
第一集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
你安全吗
穆特尼独立日
穆特尼无法撼动网络巨头
新闻
市政厅
漫画书角
高科技休闲村
蓝月亮  操纵杆拿到了吗
有好东西换就行
你安全吗
很开心能替它找到个好人家  今晚交换吗
什么意思
我是本地人  你也是吗
我们可以见个面  操纵杆换两个1200调制解调器
下午5点怎么样
你安全吗
穆特尼系统管理员
搜索用户
汤姆·兰顿  德州  达拉斯
活动账户: 在线
BGM: "They All Laughed"
*克里斯托弗·哥伦布说地球是圆的*
*They all laughed at Christopher Columbus*
*他们都笑了  哈哈*
*When he said the world was round, aha*
*爱迪生实现录音  他们都笑了*
*They all laughed when Edison recorded sound...*
*莱特兄弟说人能飞起来*
*They all laughed at Wilbur and his brother*
*他们都笑了*
*When they said that man could fly*
*他们告诉马可尼无线电就是胡扯*
*They told Marconi wireless was a phony...*
他在唱弗兰克·辛纳屈的歌吗
Is he doing Frank Sinatra?
他唱弗兰克·扎帕我也不在乎
He can do Frank Zappa for all I care.
只要能拖住他就行
As long as it holds him off.
好了  再启动她一次试试
All right, let's cycle her through again.
-她  -对  她
- Her? - Yeah, her.
喜怒不定  特别难养
Temperamental, high-maintenance,
只有好生伺候才给好脸色
only responds to the right touch.
我都伺候这玩意半年了
Yeah, well, I've been touching this thing for six months
而"他"还是没法运行
and he still hasn't turned on.
*洛克菲勒要建大厦  他们都笑了*
*They all laughed at Rockefeller Center*
*现在他们削尖了脑袋往里钻*
*Now they're fightin' to get in*
*穆特尼想造新机器  他们都笑了*
*They all laughed at Mutiny and our cotton gin...*
*他们说我们永远没出息*
*They all said we never would be happy*
*他们嘲笑我们*
*They laughed at us, and how*
*可是啊可是*
*But, oh, ho-ho*
*看谁笑到了最后*
*Who's got the last laugh now?*
能麻烦你下楼催催他们吗
Hey, could you make them hurry up downstairs?
-好好  -这人眼看就要走了
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah. - We're gonna lose this dude.
终于看见这儿来了几位女士
Hey, it's nice to see some ladies here for once.
既然想给主机正式启动运行
Probably should've waited to schedule the celebration
办一场庆典
of a working mainframe
那就该等到主机能够启动运行时再办
until the mainframe was actually, you know, working.
博斯让你们快点  记者快等不及了
Hey, Bos says hurry up. That reporter's gonna leave.
好
Yeah.
好了  再试试
All right, try that.
还是启动不了
Still not booting up.
你还好吗
You okay?
还行
Yeah.
十分制  到几分了
Scale of one to 10?
我没事
I'm fine.
你想躺躺吗
Do you want to lie down?
我当然想躺着
Yeah, of course I want to lie down.
我连轴转了一整天了
I've been awake for 20 hours.
我只是
I just...
十分制  到几分了
Scale of one to 10?
2分
Two.
最多3分
Three, max.
我再检查检查电源吧
Mm, let me check the power unit again.
现在  闲话少说
And now, please, without further ado,
隆重有请我们的创始人  卡梅伦·豪伊
let's welcome our founder, Cameron Howe.
快来
Come on.
来吧
*他们笑我对你的渴望*
*They laughed at me wanting you*
*说那不过是*
*Said it would be...*
卡梅伦·豪伊
Cameron Howe.
《资讯世界》  罗斯·韦弗
Ross Weaver, "InfoWorld."
很热闹啊  但或许有点开早了
Quite a party, but, um, maybe a little premature.
说真的  还有多久
Seriously, how much longer?
天啊  有人在绕线上放了根烟蒂
Oh, God, somebody put a cigarette out on this wire wrap.
一等我们有自己的网络
You know, once we're our own network,
卡梅伦和我就能继续做真正重要的事了
Cameron and I can get back to what really matters.
她肯定也急着拉你回去
I'm sure she's eager to get you back.
启动了吗
Booting up?
开了
It's on!
死星上线运行了
The Death Star is online and operational.
奥德兰星球会被打得七荤八素
Alderaan will never know what hit it.
唐娜  卡梅要你赶快上去
Hey, Donna. Cam wants you upstairs like right now.
好啊  咱们去庆祝吧
Yes. Let's go celebrate.
*毕竟呀毕竟  看谁笑到了最后*
*Because, ho-ho-ho, who's got the last laugh?*
*让过去也大笑吧*
*Hee-hee-hee, let's make the past laugh*
*看谁笑到了最后*
*Har-har-har, who's got the last laugh now?*
好啦  见鬼去吧  远程网
All right! Suck it, Telenet,
再也不用你们了
you faxed us your last invoice!
这爆竹比说好的多好多
That is way more fireworks than we talked about.
发言  发言
Speech! Speech!
上吧
Hey, come on.
好啦  好啦
Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
首先  我要感谢《资讯世界》的
Okay, first of all, I would like to welcome
罗斯·韦弗赏光前来
our guest, Ross Weaver, from "InfoWorld."
希望你们都跟他聊过了
I hope you've all had a chance to talk to him.
他会报道我们的重装上阵
He'll be covering our relaunch.
毒品都藏好咯
Hide the drugs.
大家都知道上周我们的用户数突破十万
As you know, we hit 100,000 users last week.
太好了
Yeah!
但更重要的是
But, more importantly,
今天是升旗日  伙计们
it's a banner day, you guys.
我们的独立日
Our Independence Day!
还有一件事
Oh, oh, one more thing.
很重要
This is very important.
约翰·博斯沃思正式当上爷爷了
John Bosworth is officially a grandfather.
我知道我们好像是才搬来加州
Look, I know it feels like we got to California two minutes ago,
但我们还不能松懈
but we can't slow down now.
我们要继续扩充网上的用户体验
We are continuing to expand user experience on the network...
改进头像  扩建社区
Avatar modification, building out neighborhoods.
大量重要工作最近就得完成了
We have a ton of really important deadlines coming up
全靠各位了
and we are counting on you guys.
我们知道这是多么艰难
We know how hard it was
离开我们德州的亲朋好友
to leave all our friends and family in Texas,
但是你们的付出让我们非常感动
but we are so impressed with your commitment
-我们想...  -说到付出
- and we just want-- - Speaking of commitment,
我要特别感谢一个人
there is one person I would especially like to thank--
我丈夫戈登·克拉克
my husband Gordon Clark.
快上来
Come on up.
戈登
Gordo!
我只想说非常感谢你
I just want to say thank you so much
相信这个疯狂的想法
for believing in this crazy idea
跟我一起在地下室埋头苦干
and slaving away in the basement with me,
没有你我们不可能做到
because we couldn't have done it without you.
我不可能做到
I couldn't have.
好了  来吧  我们继续狂欢
All right, come on, let's get back to the party.
没有你我不可能做到  戈登
I couldn't have done it without you, Gordon.
可不是  没有你的钱不可能做到
Yeah, couldn't have done it without your money.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
这完全是恶意攻击
This is a complete hatchet job.
我知道很难听  但是相信我
I know it hurts, but, trust me,
没有什么报道是糟糕的报道
there's no such thing as bad press.
专业版的报纸风评一败涂地
And the Pro got creamed in the trades
但销量仍是巨人的五倍
and it still outsold the Giant by a factor of five.
不  这不一样  这太糟了
No, this is different. This is bad.
怎么  我猜猜  你要杀了他吗
What, let me guess. You're gonna kill him?
是他列举的事实要我们的命
No, it's his facts that are killing us.
我们的规模是计算机服务的四分之一
We're a quarter of the size of CompuServe,
我们的基础设施比百源少
we have less infrastructure than The Source,
我们的投资预期比科灵可差得多
nowhere near the investment visibility of Q-Link.
我讨厌这文章  但他说得对
I hate it, but he's right.
-怎么样  小家伙  -《家庭马戏团》还是很烂
- What's up, squirt? - "Family Circus" still sucks.
-没错  -别说脏话
- That's true. - Hey, language.
别说脏话
Language.
-琼妮去哪了  -穿衣服
- Where is Joanie? - Getting dressed.
他说你们是新贵  欢迎你们
He calls you upstarts, says you're a welcome addition
给硅谷增添生命活力
of heart and vitality to the Valley landscape.
那家伙...这很好啊
The guy's-- that's great.
他还说我们到88年就得完蛋
Yeah, he's also got us going under by '88.
如果你那么担心
Well, if you're that worried about it,
发个新闻稿  公布各种收益数据
issue a press release full of stats and revenue
讲出你的说法
and, you know, tell your version of the story.
什么  没人看新闻稿
What? No one reads press releases.
他们就看杂志  像这本
They read magazines, like this one.
那我们不如写个讣告得了
Well, then, we might as well write an obituary.
-妈的  -别说脏话
- Oh, shit. - Language.
对不起
Sorry, honey.
我今天4点要见琼妮的校长
I've got to meet with Joanie's principal today at 4:00.
为什么
Why?
她周一打架了
She got in a fight on Monday.
你本打算什么时候告诉我的
Okay, when were you gonna tell me about that?
抱歉  我完全忘了
I'm sorry. Completely forgot.
她起码赢了吧
She win, at least?
校方要找家长
The school wants a parent meeting.
我们4点有个发展会议
Uh, we have a development meeting at 4:00.
-我知道  -他去不行吗
- I know. - So, can't he do it?
好吧  我给你们一点时间
Okay, I'll give you guys a minute.
哇啊
Roar!
哇啊  抓住你了
Roar! Got you.
你刚才完全不知道我在这儿
You totally didn't know I was in there.
嗯  你可是因为
Yeah, well, you're totally busted
在学校打架被抓到了
for the fight you got into at school.
不管  反正我揍扁了她
Whatever. I kicked her ass.
-真的吗  -你弄吧  你知道你想的
- Really? - Go ahead. You know you want to.
什么
What?
你真是个小调皮
You're such a little brat.
我还
And I-- -
我知道你很不爽  我也是
I know you're frustrated. I'm frustrated, too.
我们五个人挤在这里
We're five people living on top of each other, and that's--
唐娜  我不爽是因为这本该是临时的
Donna, I'm frustrated because this was supposed to be temporary.
-这的确是  -不  已经六个月了
- It is temporary. - No, it's been six mo--
该死
Oh, shit.
海莉  亲爱的  到桌子底下去
Haley, sweetheart, get under the table.
琼妮
Joanie!
-妈  -没事了  没事
- Mom! - It's okay, it's okay.
没事了  你还好吧
It's all right. You okay?
-刚才是  -是  别过来  有碎玻璃
- Was that...? - Yes, it was. Hang on, there's broken glass here.
我们该怎么办  去门廊还是出去
What should we do? Should we stay in the doorway or go outside?
你没事  原地别动就行
You're fine. You're fine right where you are.
琼妮  宝贝  你没事吧
Joanie, baby, are you okay?
我没事  别对我大惊小怪的
I'm fine, just don't freak out on me.
抱歉  你觉得那只是小震
Sorry, do you think that was just a preview?
更大的在后面吗
Like a bigger one's coming?
-或者这就完了  -听着
- Or is that the final thing? - Hey, listen.
-你别帮倒忙了  -别这么怂  海莉
- You're not helping. - Don't be such a wimp, Haley.
-琼妮  -你妹妹受了惊吓  态度好点
- Hey, Joanie. - Your sister's scared. Be nice.
-你总是帮她说话  -琼妮
- You always take her side. - Joanie.
大家听着
Hey, listen, guys.
天哪  只是吐司而已啊
Jesus, people, it's toast.
你看上去真炫
My, don't you look out of this world.
是不是很酷
Pretty rad, right?
触角这周刚上线
The antennae just rolled out this week,
还有太阳镜  常规眼镜
along with sunglasses, regular glasses,
以及个性化的莫霍克头
and a Mohawk customization.
你真该弄个莫霍克头
You should totally get the Mohawk.
我们应该走动一下
Oh, we should totally get going.
先去主干道  再去小地方
Let's start with Main Street and then the smaller places.
大锤来了
Oh, there's Sledgehammer.
你听说计算机服务扩展到日本了吗
Did you hear CompuServe's expanding to Japan?
通用电气信息交换网络上季度增加了一万个用户
And GEnie added 10,000 users last quarter.
至少CBS可能会退出特林克斯
At least CBS might back out of Trintex.
真好  那就只剩IBM和西尔斯了
Great, then it's just IBM and Sears.
感觉好冷清啊  是吧
Seems kind of dead on here, doesn't it?
是啊  周二早上9点
Well, yeah, at 9:00 a.m. on a Tuesday
系统就像上午的赌场一样冷清
and the system's like a casino floor in the morning.
只有铁杆粉
It's only the hardcores.
但看看漫画书角
But, hey, look at Comic Book Corner.
小房间的人数
Oh, the niche room metrics
永远是爆表的
are off the charts 'round the clock.
这地方好热闹
That place is rowdy, man.
这里的争吵比地狱天使吧还多
There's more fights than a Hells Angels bar.
幸好这些人的眼镜是虚拟的
Well, I guess it's good that these guys' glasses are digital, then.
真逗  等等
Nice. Oh, hold on a sec.
他有改装开火按钮的1311操纵杆
Guy's got a 1311 with a modded thumbfire button.
天哪  你认识这里的每一个人吗
Jeez, do you know everybody on here?
就是这里了
And then here we are.
6.4万像素  全部有待开发
64,000 pixels of prime, undeveloped real estate.
我们想要它做什么都行
It can be whatever we want it to be.
必须得是
It's got to be--
必须得是非常了不起的东西
it's gotta be something great.
莱恩  怎么了
Ryan. What's up?
抱歉  我无意打扰
Sorry, I didn't mean to interrupt.
我们还谈吗  我们说好了是9点
Are we still on? I know we said 9:00.
-还是9点15  -不  就是9点
- Maybe it was 9:15. - No, it was 9:00.
对  是9点  进来吧
Yeah, no, 9:00. Come on in.
我不知道
I don't know.
有另一种方式来看
Okay, here's another way to look at it.
社区就像这样
Community looks like this.
不  应该是这样
No, uh, it looks like this.
不  像这样
Well, no, like this.
反正就是聊天之类的
Just-- okay, blah, blah, chatting, chatting, chatting.
我们用精灵单元界面来包装它
We dress it up with a sprite-scaling interface,
但其本质只是数字绘画
but underneath it's just paint-by-numbers.
这里有个房间  去里面聊天
You know, here's a room, chat in it.
没那么简单吧
I think it's a little more than paint-by-numbers.
别忘了有意义的人际交流
To discount the meaningful human interaction.
不  它挺好  没啥问题
No, no, no, it works, it's fine.
就像香草冰激凌  但是...
It's like vanilla ice cream, but it's...
这是用户  这是私聊室
So, here are the users and here's private chat.
这些用户在聊天
And the users, they're talking, talking.
"一切都好吗
"Hey, what's going on?
我们增进一下对彼此的了解吧"
Let's get to know each other more."
因此他们选择了私聊
So they go to private chat.
私聊使用的是PETSCII  这是...
And then private chat is just PETSCII because--
PET电脑的信息交换标准码
1977年的
1977.
PET发售时间为1977年
你妈总会告诉你随手关门吧
You know how your mom always says to close the door behind you?
这两个用户  他们离开聊天室
These two users, they-- they leave,
却不关上门...
and they don't close the...
其他那些人在说
Okay, so, all these other people here are saying,
"你们在干什么呢
"hey, what are you guys doing?
他们要去哪里  我想去看看"
Where are they going? I want to check that out."
他们就跟着去  像这样
And so they-- they go, like that.
所以
And so...
这就是你们的问题
that's your problem.
你们看过《窃听大阴谋》[对话]吗
Have you guys ever seen "The Conversation"?
什么对话
Which conversation?
等等  吉恩·哈克曼那部电影
Wait, the-- the Gene Hackman movie?
没错
Exactly.
人们以为私聊是私密的
People think private chat is private.
但由于某人编写的代码...
But because of the way somebody wrote it--
-是我写的代码  -等一下
- The way I wrote it. - Wait, wait.
你是说有人在黑进私聊里
You're telling me that people are hacking private chats?
是啊  经常的
Sure, um, big-time.
你看
Look.
看见这个小家伙了吗
So, see this little guy here?
这就是那个黑客  身份是隐藏的
That's the hacker. Totally masked.
星号是数据提示符  这个掩盖不了
The asterisk is a prompt for data. You can't mask that.
等等  你怎么拿到这个的
Hold on. How did you get this?
这是私聊抄本
These are private chat transcripts.
简单  我跟着黑客从同一个漏洞进去的
Easy, I just walked through the gaping holes that the hackers did.
-莱恩  -不行  你不能那么做
- Ryan. - No, you cannot do that.
我当然可以  我只是...
Sure, I can. I just--
别再那么做了  真的
Don't do it again. I mean it.
这直接违反了我们的用户协议
That's a direct violation of our user agreement.
好吧  说得没错
Yeah, okay. Um, totally right.
我的想法是这样的
Uh, but here's my idea.
在公共聊天室外将用户连接起来
So, you connect users outside public room,
但首先将他们连到不同的加密节点
but to different encryption points first,
再让他们互相连接
then to each other.
掩盖连接轨迹
You cover tracks,
重新建立
you rebuild private chat
独立于穆特尼的私聊室
separate from Mutiny,
同时又从外部向穆特尼通信
but also still talking to Mutiny outside Mutiny.
是另一个完全独立的穆特尼
Second but separate Mutiny.
用户在这里  这里  和这里
Users here, here, and here
网络  远程  程序  中枢
network, remote, program, hub,
RSA加密  过滤器一  二  三
RSA, filters one, two, three.
没有缓存  搞定
No cache. Voila.
莱恩  这是个全新且昂贵的东西
Ryan, that's an entirely new and very expensive something
运用的技术我们的编程员根本不会  所以...
using techniques that our coders don't even know, so...
我能做  我能做
I can do it. I can do it.
你还有一大堆精灵渲染代码没交给我
You still have a ton of sprite rendering for me.
那就让做不了这个的人去做那个吧
Then put one of the guys who can't do this on it.
莱恩  我们不会做的
Ryan, we're not doing it.
好吧
Okay.
但我还有另一个想法
But here's another idea.
好吧  这样好吗
Okay, you know what?
莱恩  不如你电邮给我们怎么样
Ryan, why don't you just send it to us electronically?
好的
Okay.
好  没问题
Cool. No problem.
很好  我们都很期待你的想法
Great, really looking forward to checking it out.
我要再提一下
Oh, and just to say it one more time,
这种东西对于穆特尼来说
something like this is way better for Mutiny
比给头像加领带好太多了
than putting a bow tie on an avatar.
知道了  谢谢
Got it. Yeah, thanks.
又来了
It's happening again!
前六次还是很好笑的
It was funny the first six times.
谁再玩一次就等着内裤套头吧
Next person that does it is gonna wear their underwear as a hat.
别玩了  白痴
Cut it out, you cretins.
你们每次胡闹
Every time you screw around,
墙屑都会撒落在主机上
it rains down debris on the mainframe.
看  现在还有日期了
Look. There's a date now.
兄弟  那就是今天
Dude, that's today.
要我说  肯定是里根搞的鬼
If you ask me, it's got Reagan's fingerprints all over it.
-拜托  -还记得太空激光计划吗
- Jesus. - Hello, remember Lasers in Space?
一开始是因为害怕
Okay, it starts with fear
因为没人想死于核爆
because nobody wants to die in a nuclear blast.
然后  他们一条条地夺走你的权利
And then, one by one, they take away your rights
直到你对里根高呼万岁
until you're Sieg Heilin' Ronnie
并跪舔埃德·米斯and bowing down before Ed Meese.
前司法部长
肯定是跟同性恋有关
It's gotta be some gay thing.
像艾滋什么的
You know, like AIDS.
真会说话  兄弟
Real sensitive, dude.
也许是跟宗教有关
Maybe it's a religious thing,
像是帕特·罗伯逊说的世界要再次毁灭了
like Pat Robertson saying the world's gonna end again.
传媒大亨
前美南浸信会牧师
一群笨蛋
You idiots.
-是乔·麦克米伦  -什么
- It's Joe MacMillan. - Wait, what?
-不可能  -不会吧
- No way! - Nyet.
这比里根还有意思
Oh, that's better than Reagan.
杀毒那家伙
The antivirus guy?
-你怎么这么肯定  -他们原本是搭档
- How are you so sure? - They were partners.
他真的认识麦当娜吗
Is it true he knows Madonna?
私下认识
Like, really knows her?
我听说他第一个客户是中情局
I heard his first client was the CIA.
不对  那是甲骨文公司
Yeah, no, that was Oracle.
麦克米伦不是偷了你的点子
Didn't MacMillan, like, steal your idea
然后大赚了一笔吗
and make a gazillion dollars?
是啊
Yeah.
但我要起诉他  知道吧
But I'm suing the son of a bitch, aren't I?
没有  我直接睡过去了
No, I slept right through it.
我醒了以后  发现厕所水泼出来点
I woke up and some water had sloshed out the toilet bowl,
但也仅此而已
but that was about it.
但是听我说  特里
But, look, Terry,
我想赶在再大震之前
before the big one hits...
搞定调制解调器的订单
I want to get this modem order sorted out.
没错  V.22
You're damn right, v.22.
给我个批发价吧
Hey, and I want the wholesale number for that.
特里...别这样  老兄
Ter-- oh, come on, man.
我完全可以去街对面的机器人公司
I can walk right across the street to USR
还能很快拿货
and get high-speed transfer for that.
就...
Just--
好吧  你想谈的时候给我打电话
all right, well, call me back when you want to talk,
等你清醒了的  行吗
when you've come to your senses, all right?
多谢
Thanks.
听着  你得...
Look, you need to--
你得给主机室买些设备了
you need to invest in some improvements in the mainframe room.
不然肯定要出事
It's a disaster waiting to happen.
行  你需要咱们就买
All right, whatever you need.
没问题
No problem.
还有别的事吗  戈登
There something else, Gordon?
你是怎么做到的
How do you do it?
你怎么忍得了他们这样胡闹
How do you deal with all this nonsense?
就像在动物园里喂动物
You know, it's like feeding animals at the zoo.
用几块腌鱼就能逗得他们跳舞
Dangle a couple kippers out for them and they dance
让他们安心在笼子里关一整天
and keep them locked up in their cages the rest of the day.
如果你是指那两位丛林女王
You talking about the queens of the jungle,
就另当别论了
that's a different story.
想听建议吗
Advice?
别去妨碍军师团才是上策
I find it wise not to interfere with the brain trust.
这是她们的地盘  我只是个打工的
They run the place. I just work here.
博斯沃思
Bosworth.
男孩还是女孩
Boy or girl?
-什么  -男孩还是女孩
- Excuse me? - Boy or girl?
你的孙辈
Your grandchild.
是个男孩
Oh, it's, uh-- he's a boy.
你是谁
Who is this?
你真的忘记我了吗
Come on, did you really forget about me?
-乔  -我只是想说  我为你感到高兴
- Joe? - I just wanted to call and say I'm happy for you.
你怎么拿到...
Hey, how did you even get the--
保重  约翰
Be well, John.
十万用户听起来是不错
Yeah, 100,000 users sounds good,
但问题是他们能在线多久
but what really matters is how long they stay on.
而事实证明
And moving that number
提升在线时长是很难的
is proving a lot more difficult than it looks.
听着
Hey, listen.
弄好主机后
Once I get the mainframe solid,
我想
I was thinking...
我也说不好
I don't know,
我想去找找别的工作
I was thinking about maybe pursuing other opportunities.
3033已经调试好了
We did what we set out to do with the 3033
这里也不怎么需要我了
and, come on, there's not really much more for me to do.
好吧
Well...
我希望你能开心
I want you to be happy.
你们是琼妮的父母吧
I'm guessing you two are Joanie's mom and dad.
你是詹妮弗的妈妈吗
Oh, are you Jennifer's mom?
大部分时间是  大家也叫我黛安
Most of the time. People also call me Diane.
你好  我是唐娜
Of course. I'm Donna.
戈登  抱歉
Oh, Gordon, sorry.
就琼妮来说
Look, as far as Joanie goes,
我知道插班生的日子不好过
I know how hard it is to be the new kid in school.
我挺同情她的
She has my sympathy.
但归根结底
But I think what this boils down to
还是因为詹妮弗很生她爸和我的气
is Jennifer is just pretty pissed at her father and me.
我们正在办理手续
We're going through proceedings.
事情不是很顺利
It's been a bit rocky.
手续
Pr-- proceedings?
离婚
Divorce.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
我不觉得  相信我  这样对大家都好
Oh, I'm not. Believe me, it's better for everyone.
除了詹妮弗  她在闹脾气
Except Jennifer, who's lashing out.
总之  我很抱歉
Anyway, so, I apologize
希望没有给你们造成太多困扰
and I hope it hasn't caused you too much grief.
克拉克夫妇  古德太太
Uh, Mr. And Mrs. Clark. Oh, Mrs. Gould.
威尔科克斯校长可以见你们了
Principal Wilcox will see you now.
太好了
Great.
卡梅
Hey, Cam.
你跟别人说起过我孙子吗
Hey, did you tell anyone else about my grandson?
没有  我不该说出来吗
No. Should I not have announced it?
没事  就是问问
Nah, nah. I'm just wondering.
博斯  过来
Hey, Bos. Come here.
干吗
What?
我需要你给莱恩涨个工资
I need you to give Ryan a raise.
给他涨个15%
Just bump him up 15%.
好  这是好主意
All right, that's a good call.
那孩子活儿干得非常好
The kid's been doing a bang-up job.
-是啊  -好
- Yeah. - All right.
我在干活儿呢
Hey, I'm working here.
哥们  我们要去汉堡王
Dude, we're all going to Burger King.
跟我们一起去吃午饭吧
Come to lunch with us.
我带饭了  不用了
I brought today. I'm good.
得了  地下室怪人  你再这样
Come on, this Boo Radley-in-the-basement thing
就有点吓人了
is getting kind of creepy.
一起出去吃点东西嘛
We're offering you a flame-broiled way out of here.
听着  我没时间
Look, I don't have time.
这很重要  好吗
This is important, okay?
不是吧
Seriously?
随你了
Whatever.
简直像个奴隶  他还要开夜车吗
What a slave. What, does he sleep late?
对不起
I'm sorry.
何必  是我在
Why? I'm the one changing
洗手间里换衣服
in the middle of a little girls' room.
再次感谢你这么宽宏大量
Thank you again for being so understanding.
孩子就是孩子嘛
Kids'll be kids.
或许詹妮弗什么时候可以来找琼妮玩
Maybe Jennifer can come play with Joanie sometime.
那就太别扭了  她俩可讨厌彼此
Well, that would be odd considering they don't like each other.
抱歉  我会去找琼妮谈谈的
I'm sorry. I'll talk to Joanie.
我觉得我们养了两个有脾气的姑娘是好事
I like it that we're both raising girls who are fighters.
你说呢
Don't you?
怎么了
What?
我就是很高兴你没被停学
I'm just glad you didn't get suspended.
我知道你觉得自己讨厌加州
I know you think you hate California.
我知道在这里挺不容易的
I know it's-- it's hard here.
但是
But...
我们得下决心
we have to commit.
否则  这里永远不会有家的感觉
Otherwise, it's never gonna feel like home.
整个房子都在晃
The whole house was shaking.
亲爱的  你没事吧
Sweetie, you okay?
我没事
I'm fine.
-真的吗  -没事
- You sure? - Fine.
我们会没事的
We are gonna be okay.
我保证
I promise.
这是涨工资  孩子
It's a raise, son.
你今天走运了
You won today.
卡梅伦和唐娜还说别的什么了吗
Did Cameron or Donna mention anything else?
比你要的少吗
Is it less than you asked for?
我根本没要什么
I didn't ask for anything.
我就是提出了些建议
I just pitched them some ideas.
等时间合适时  她们肯定会来找你的
I'm sure they'll reach out when and if the time is right.
她们肯定会再通知你的
I'm sure they'll let you know.
蓝月亮侦探吗
Blue Moon Detective?
卡梅豪伊
Oh, hey, CamHowe.
很高兴跟你见面
Nice to meet you... in person.
这样认识人怪怪的  是吧
It's weird meeting people this way, isn't it?
就好像你是从我的电脑屏幕上
It's like you jumped out of my computer screen
跳出来的  好像你不是真的
or something, like you're not real.
是啊  穆特尼这方面挺酷的
Yeah, yeah, Mutiny's pretty cool in that...
我没加入多久  我才发现的
I haven't been on long. I only just discovered it.
你呢
How about you?
我在那里工作
I work there, actually.
那肯定挺有意思的
That's gotta be fun.
是啊  其实也不轻松的
Yeah, you know, it's harder than it looks.
是这个吗
Is this the gear?
是的  请便吧
Oh, yeah, yeah. Please go ahead.
应该就在里面
I think it's in there somewhere.
嗯
Oh, yeah.
希望这漆没关系
Hope the paint's okay.
没事  他生前是四九人队的球迷吧
Yeah, no, he was a big Niners fan, right?
是啊
Yeah, he was.
你怎么知道的
How do you know about that?
什么
What?
他生前是...
That he was a--
等等  我们提到过他吗
wait, did we talk about him?
-嗯  -我儿子
- Yeah. - My son.
是啊  你在哀悼互助聊天室里发过帖子
Yeah, yeah. You posted in the grief and support room.
请节哀顺变
And I'm so sorry for your loss,
但是  操纵杆看上去很好
but the, um, joystick looks great, so--
我们不是在哀悼版块认识的
We didn't meet on the grief board.
是在科技聊天室里
We met in the tech room.
是啊
Right.
我们是在那儿认识的  但我看到
That's where we met, but I saw that you posted
你在哀悼互助聊天室里发的帖了
in the grief and support room and then--
我只发了...
All I posted was--
我只是说我失去了亲人
I mean, I just posted that I had lost someone.
我没提到过...
I never said anything about...
我只是跟其他人私聊过他的事
I just had private chats about him with other people.
-没提什么...  -是啊
- Not anything-- - No.
我们没谈到过他  从来没有
We never talked about him, never.
你怎么知道那事的
How-- how the hell do you know about that?
你怎么知道他的
How do you know about him at all?
我...
I...
我该走了
I think I should go.
你怎么知道我儿子的
How do you know about my son?
那些对话不是受隐私保护的吗
Those conversations were supposed to be private.
干吗  你能怪我吗
What, can you blame me?
为了给聊天室增加图形处理能力忙前忙后的
All this to add graphics capability to chat.
只要能让用户在线更久就行
Whatever keeps the users on longer.
很怀疑能奏效多久
Seriously doubt it'll work long.
是啊  但这个LZW压缩蛮酷的
Yeah, but this LZW compression is pretty cool.
你真觉得人们会为了动图而多看两眼吗
You really think people are gonna stick around because of GIFs?
-那个叫JIF  -少来  是GIF
- It's pronounced "Jif." - No way. Hard G, "Gif."
我听说是JIF  你想说错的随你
I heard "Jif," but it's cool if you want to be wrong.
看啊  是"乔丹"
Hey, look, everyone, it's "Jordon."
你们知道你们的话我在
Hey, you guys know I can hear everything you say
主机室里听得一清二楚吧
down in the mainframe room?
嗯  这个你听得到吗
Yeah, can you hear this?
马蒂  我真替你担心
Marty, I worry about you.
我无意中听到
What I couldn't help but overhear
你们为加班而抱怨
is you guys whining about having a long night.
在卡迪夫杀戮室
Back in the Cardiff kill room,
我们开发了一项
we developed a little technique
专门针对熬夜的技巧
for pushing through nights like this.
叫做"混搭提神"
Called it the "Tandy-Shandy."
一罐提神  一罐是
One keeps you sharp, and the other's--
啤酒
the other's a beer.
我们自己也有技巧
Well, we've got our own technique,
你感兴趣吗
if you're interested.
先生们  这就是给恐龙打飞机的方式
And that, gentlemen, is how you jerk off a dinosaur.
好了  我得去打个电话
All right, now, look, I'm gonna make a phone call.
等我回来  跟我讲讲那姑娘的事
When I come back, I wanna hear about that Amiga.
好吗
All right?
博斯沃思  请留言
Bosworths, leave a message.
儿子  是老爸
Hey there, son. It's Dad.
你现在大概也习惯
I suppose you're getting used to calling yourself
这么称呼自己了吧
that right about now, huh?
真是的  洛克维尔这会儿挺晚了吧
Oh, hell, I bet it's getting late in Rockwall.
该死
Dang it.
希望我没把我的小宝贝吵醒了
I hope I didn't wake my little sweet pea up there.
真抱歉我老错过你
I'm sorry I keep missing you.
我就是想听到那孩子的一切
I just want to hear every little detail about that kid.
我意识到我还不知道
It would occur to me I don't even know
他叫什么呢
the little fella's name.
你们想好了吗...
Did you guys decide on one or--
于是
So...
我去了乔家
So I go over to Joe's house,
我还以为这家伙
you know, I'm expecting to see this guy
已经上吊自杀了
swinging from the rafters.
老天爷
Holy shit.
但是  他居然还活着
But, surprise, he's alive.
他打开了门  样子狼狈极了
He opens the door. I mean, he looks like hell,
但他还活着
but he's alive.
于是我进去了
So, I go in.
那里已经完全清空了
You know, the whole place is cleaned out.
我看得出  他的整个人生都毁了
And I can see it, his whole life gone,
完蛋了
destroyed.
跟我猜得一样
It's exactly what I had thought,
所以我才整夜没睡
which is exactly why I stayed up all night
逆向索纳里斯的代码
reversing the Sonaris code.
老实说  我是真心想帮他
You know, honestly, I really wanted to help him.
所以我出于好心  把光盘给了他
So I gave him the disk out of the goodness of my heart.
我们还拥抱了
We hugged.
乔·麦克米伦还会拥抱
Joe MacMillan knows how to hug?
接下来  我一觉醒来
Next thing you know, I wake up,
就发现他筹资一千万的事
I'm reading about $10 million in financing,
都是靠了我的软件
all based on my software.
太过分了
That's insane.
是啊
Yeah.
他那种人当然会偷你的点子
Of course a guy like that would steal your idea.
他太笨了  自己想不到
I mean, he's too stupid to come up with one of his own.
不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
别那么做
Don't you do that.
别低估他
Don't you underestimate him.
你低估他时  他才最危险
That's when he's most dangerous.
不  乔
No, Joe's...
乔非常聪明
Joe's brilliant.
你如果被他控制住了
And when you're in that guy's thrall,
那感觉就像吸毒一样
you know, it feels like a drug.
你会觉得
You know, you-- you feel...
自己是世上最重要的人
like the most important person in the world.
这时候  你就会一觉醒来发现自己被他割喉
And that's when you wake up with your neck slit,
血流了一地
bleeding all over the floor.
那是什么
What is that?
雷的私聊抄本
They're Ryan's private chat transcripts.
他都已经打出来了
He'd already printed them off
我就想  或许能从中找到什么答案
and I figured maybe there'd be some answers in here,
但是  如果我们真挺不过88年呢
but what if we do go under by '88?
我们去年经历的一切
I mean, everything we went through last year,
所有的抗争
all the battles we fought,
然后又举家搬迁
moving everything out here, everyone, our--
离开家人和朋友
leaving our families and our friends.
如果我们做了这么多
What if we did all that just to, what,
最终却只能在这儿活跃几年
putter around out here for a couple of years
然后就像
and then disappear like
从没来过一样消失了呢
we were never even here in the first place?
不  搬来这里不是个错误
No, moving here wasn't a mistake.
给我
Here.
这里面肯定有答案的
There's gotta be something in here.
人们下线的理由有很多
Well, there's all kinds of reasons that people are signing off.
聊得太投机
They're getting along so well,
想打电话聊
they want to talk on the phone.
或许这是显然原因
Maybe that's obvious.
有时他们甚至想当面见
Sometimes they even want to meet up in person.
或者是想做交易
Or they want to make a trade.
我早些时候去见那个卖操纵杆的人了
I met up with the joystick guy earlier.
那你干吗还买外卖了
Then why did you go to Fry's?
因为  我见到他时
Because when I met up with him in person,
才发现他是个变态
he turned out to be a total creep.
线上交易
Transactional interactions?
如果你想做交易
Like, what if you didn't have to sign off
也不需线下进行
when you wanted to make a trade?
-你可以  -在网上交易
- You could just... - Do it online.
好吧
Okay, sure.
你是这么做的  但这只是一个原因...
That's just what you did, but that's only one reason--
好吧  我们是不能阻止人们
Okay, look. We're never gonna stop people
煲电话粥的
from talking on the phone, right?
我们也不想那么做
And we don't want to because that's...
因为那才是真正的交心
a genuine connection.
但交易
But with transactions...
看
Here, look!
这是讲私制唱片的
This is about bootlegs.
"我有去年秋天的威尼斯表演"
"I've got the Venice show from last fall."
"我有北部整个夏天的"
"I've got the whole summer up north."
这里又一个
Here's another one!
看  拿我的《85版摔角狂热》
Here. How about my "WrestleMania '85"
换你的汉格勒和赫恩斯《大战》的录像带  好吗
for your Hagler/Hearns "War" VHS?
不会都是这个
It's not gonna be every time,
但可能有足够多的交易
but there could be enough of these
值得我们建个线上服务
that it warrants building something
让人们可以在穆特尼上进行这方面交互
so that people are doing this interaction on Mutiny.
就算人们现在没在做线上交易
Even if people aren't already trading,
这也终归是种新的交互形式
it's a brand-new type of interaction
或许能吸引越来越多的用户
that could draw in more and more users.
是啊  如果足够好的话
Yeah, yeah. If it's good enough.
必须得做得够好
It just has to be good enough.
好吧
Okay, that's...
这有点意思
That's interesting.
我没见过这种东西
I've never seen that before.
但这是制胜绝招吗
But is this it?
我不知道
I-I don't know.
我也没见过这种东西
I've never seen it before, either,
我们似乎已经见识过不少东西了
and I feel like we've seen a lot.
这样的东西
This could be the sort of thing
或许能真正吸引
that would make people really sit up
人们的注意
and pay attention.
-但这是绝招吗  -是吧
- But is it it? - Right?
因为这必须是绝招
'Cause it needs to be it,
因为我们在这里只有一次机会
'cause we're only gonna get one shot at this out here.
好吧
Well...
主机一切都好吧
Everything okay with the mainframe?
嗯
Yep.
搞定了
Took care of it.
总之  我借此跟程序员们聊了会儿
Anyways, it gave me an excuse to hang out with the coders.
-嗯  -混搭提神吗
- You know. - Tandy-Shandy?
还不止
And then some.
你们在研究什么吗
You guys working on something?
是啊  我们在考虑些想法
Oh, yeah, we were just coming up with some ideas--
交给你们军师团了
I'll leave it to the brain trust.
好吧  他可真怪
Okay, that was so weird.
你觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
我们试试吧
I think let's do it.
我也这么觉得
Yeah, I think so, too.
但如果想成功
But if this is gonna work,
我们就得信任彼此
we're gonna have to trust each other.
读私人聊天记录违反了我们的用户协议
Reading private chats is a violation of our user agreement.
我们能关闭那个代码里的后门吗
Can we close the back door of that code?
当然
Yeah, sure.
没问题
No problem.
你磕大了
You're high.
你也是
Yeah, so are you.
你一股大学生的味儿  戈登
You smell like Berkeley, Gordon.
-我可以去洗洗  -不用
- I could take a shower. - No.
我们的卧室里多久没有大麻味儿了
When's the last time our bedroom smelled like weed?
这就是加州的妙处
That's the great thing about California.
我们的卧室随时可以一股大麻味儿
Our bedroom can smell like weed whenever we want.
恐惧
Fear--
是接近真相时的自然反应
it's a natural reaction to moving closer to the truth.
自从我成立了麦克米伦实用网络
You know, ever since I started MacMillan Utility,
就一直有人说我在兜售恐惧
I've been accused of selling fear.
但我问问你们
But let me ask you...
是恐惧吗
is it fear?
还是真相
Or is it truth?
我们的立足点究竟有多稳定
How sure is our footing?
昨天早晨  当我们脚下的大地颤动时
Yesterday morning, many of us were reminded of that question
很多人脑中再次浮现出了这个问题
when we literally felt the ground move beneath us.
我们所生活的世界一直在改变
We live in a world that is constantly shifting,
有时候  它将我们聚在一起
sometimes bringing us together
有时候又将我们拆散
and sometimes pulling us apart.
老爸  别担心打来得太晚
Hey, Pop, don't worry about calling late.
我们都放弃睡觉了
We already gave up on sleep.
总之  你会想知道
Anyway, uh, I thought you'd like to know
我们决定叫他萨缪尔·约翰
we are going with Samuel John.
我们的朋友都是谁
Who are our friends?
我们的敌人是谁
Who are our enemies?
我们将会如何
What's gonna happen to us?
我们安全吗
Are we safe?
我的创造已有所发展
What I created has grown.
你们中有些人
Now, some of you...
甚至将麦克米伦实用网络称为
...even call MacMillan Utility the gold standard
公司杀毒保护的黄金标准
in corporate antivirus protection.
但同时  我一直在问自己
But in the meantime, I've been asking myself,
"安全的代价究竟该有多高
"What should the price of security really be?
我们该花多少钱
How much should we pay
来买安全的感觉"
to feel safe?"
等等  再说一条
Wait, here's another one
传统给我们的启迪
from that same ancient tradition.
存在的秘诀就在于无所畏惧
The whole secret of existence is to have no fear at all.
不要惧怕你会变成的样子
Never fear what will become of you.
不要依靠任何人
Depend on no one.
当你拒绝了一切帮助时
Only in the moment that you reject all help
你才真正自由了
are you really free.
只有克服恐惧
Only by moving past fear
我们才能获得真相
can we ever arrive at the truth.
真相就是  摆脱恐惧是种权利
And the truth is freedom from fear is a right,
而非商品
not a commodity.
我知道你们在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
我向我的企业客户要价数百万
I charge my corporate clients millions.
他们买得起
Well, they can afford it.
但明天  我将发布
But tomorrow I'm releasing
我们用户版的软件  城堡
our user version, Citadel,
那是我为你们创造的版本
the version I created for all of you.
为你们的个人电脑提供主机级别安全保障
Mainframe-quality security for your personal computer.
等等
Wait, wait.
而且我将...
And I'm charging you...
分文不取
nothing.
为你们
For you...
它是免费的
it will be absolutely free.
麦克米伦先生  我代表《资讯世界》想采访您
Mr. MacMillan, I've got a question from "InfoWorld."